Manjushyama Singhania

Mumbai | manjushyama14@gmail.com | +91 9987496921

linkedin.com/in/manjushyama-singhania-174a16211/ | github.com/ManjuShyama27

Summary

Flutter Developer with 2+ years of experience building quality-focused Android and iOS apps, delivering efficient solutions, upgrading existing applications, and turning ideas into impactful, working products

Skills

Languages: Dart,Flutter Framework

State Management: BLoC State Management, Provider

Others: Responsive Design, Firebase, API Integration, Cross-Platform Development, Agile Methodologies, Unit

Testing, Version Control, Debugging

Education

SIES College of Management Studies, Master of Computer Applications

Sept 2021 – Jun 2023

• CGPA: 8.84/10.0

SIES College of Arts, Science and Commerce, Bachelor of Information Technology

Jun 2018 - Jun 2021

• CGPA: 9.7/10.0

Experience

Systems Executive, Asian Paints – Santacruz, Mah

June 2005 – Aug 2007

- Launched a responsive application using Flutter bloc state management and clean architecture for iOS, Android, and web, resulting in a 20% increase in user engagement
- Merging multiple apps enhanced code re-usability and reduced development and deployment time for both developers and users
- Migrated an existing ionic web application to flutter and implemented new features as per business requirements
- Deployed Flutter Web Application on OpenShift, configuring reverse proxy using Apigee

Junior Software Developer Intern, CodeMischief – Vashi, Mah

Oct 2021 – Feb 2022

• Designed front-end interfaces and integrated API s for a healthcare application

Flutter Developer Intern, Collab Lab – Remote

Jun 2021 – Jul 2021

• Built gradient analysis components such as bars, gauges, and pie charts using flutter

Flutter Developer Intern, Aim2Excel – Remote

Jun 2021

• Created front-end interfaces for a learning management system

Flutter Developer Intern, Pay Services – Remote

May 2021

• Authentication implemented using Firebase for a service-oriented application

Projects

Traveln - Travel Blog Application

- Constructed a mobile application where multiple users can simultaneously view and post their travel experiences
- Tools Used: Flutter, Dart, MongoDB, Node.js, Cloudinary, Heroku

Shopify - Ecommerce Application

- Developed a ecommerce application and integrated a chatbot for customer support to enhance user experience
- Tools Used: Flutter, Dart, Firebase, Dialogflow

Certifications

- Flutter and Dart The Complete Guide Udemy
- Foundations of User Experience(UX) Design Coursera
- API Crash Course Udemy
- Git with Visual Studio Code Udemy
- Introduction to Industry 4.0 and Industrial Information of Technology NPTEL
- Discrete Mathematics NPTEL